[♪ theme music playing]
THE HUSBAND
THIS SERIES IS FICTITIOUS
CHILDREN WERE FILMED SAFELY
GEN AI WAS USED IN SELECT SCENES
EPISODE 10
[keypad beeping]
[chimes]
[door chimes]
[sighs]
[worker 1] Let's go.
Yeah, I'm coming.
I made the reservation.
Soju or beer?
-[worker 2] Let's have both.
-[worker 3] Yeah, I don't know about that.
[worker 4] Drink it all.
[♪ pensive music playing]
[door opens]
[door closes]
JI COMPUTER
[Gyeongae] Good evening.
[door unlocks]
[door opens, closes]
[keypad beeps]
[sighs]
[door chimes]
[Gyeongae] Hello.
Sir? Excuse me.
-Just a minute. Hi.
-Oh, hi.
[Gyeongae chuckles]
-Hi, there.
-[whispers] Hi.
Hey, wait. Hold on.
-[sighs]
-We've been neighbors for a while now.
I see you all the time, but I don't think
we've ever properly introduced ourselves.
[chuckles] You see, I run a little
hair salon down the alley.
Right next to the chicken place.
[Manhui whispers] Right.
-You know, down the alley…
-Yeah. Okay.
Come by when you need a haircut.
[whispers] Okay.
Hey, I'm really sorry.
Well, you look great now,
but if you got
just a tiny little trim on your bangs,
-you'd look so much better.
-[exhales]
-Drop by sometime.
-Okay.
STYLE
::cue()
Uh, wait, hold up.
I don't think I can finish
all of this on my own.
-Here, take this. Wait a minute.
-Okay.
Oh, my gosh!
Take this one instead.
Hey, wait.
[Gyeongae chuckles]
Come by for a haircut sometime!
Okay.
He's cute. [chuckles]
[sighs]
[♪ emotional music playing]
[knocks on door]
[visitor] Kim Gyeongae!
Open up.
I know you're in there.
-Come on.
-[knocks on door]
I know your lights were on until just now.
Open up while I'm being nice.
[door unlocks]
I'm not leaving empty-handed.
Come out already!
You better open up
before I kick the door down.
Or I'm going to kill you.
One.
-Two!
-[door unlocks, chimes]
-[breathing heavily]
-Look who it is. There you are.
You can't just show up like this
in the middle of the night.
[visitor] I know you made money today.
Hand it over.
[Gyeongae] You just took all of it
a few days ago.
I don't have any money right now.
[visitor] If I find a single penny
in this dump, you're dead.
-[Gyeongae grunting]
-[slap]
-I'm going to teach you a lesson!
-[Gyeongae grunting]
-[Gyeongae panting, screaming]
-[objects thudding, clattering]
-[visitor] Get your ass over here!
-[screaming continues]
-Damn it.
-[panting]
You think I'm kidding?
-Stop it.
-[visitor] Look at me.
[both grunting, groaning]
Why don't you just…
-Stop it, man.
-Get lost!
Come here. You.
What? You found yourself a guy already?
Ha! Seriously, this is ridiculous.
Come here.
-[grunts]
-[grunts, screams]
[visitor] So you've been giving
all that money to him?
-Is that right? Come here.
-[Gyeongae grunting]
[visitor] Come back here.
You don't have money to pay me,
-but you've got money for him?
-[slapping]
[visitor] So you've been busy
with your love life, huh?
I said come here!
-[grunts]
-[visitor groans]
[panting]
[breathing heavily]
Wait. Hold on.
I told you to stop it.
[thud]
I told you to stop it! [breathing heavily]
I told you to stop.
I told you, didn't I?
[sighs]
[panting]
Uh…
[panting continues]
[grunts]
STYLE
::cue()
What are you doing?
I'm calling the cops.
Hey, look at me.
If you hadn't killed this man,
I would've been dead.
From now on, just do as I say.
[breathes shakily]
[♪ tense music playing]
[chimes]
[Gyeongae] Get inside.
You're getting rained on.
Oh…
[scrubbing]
[Gyeongae humming]
[snipping]
It feels good, doesn't it?
All done.
[♪ mysterious music playing]
[stammers] Well, thank you.
For saving me.
Thank you.
THE HUSBAND
STYLE
::cue()
[Taeju] It's a list of the top sponsors
of this hospital. Have a look.
[heart monitor beeping]
The other one's the list of people
who made it into the trial.
The exact same names.
LEE SEONGUK, PARK DOHYEON
OH MINSEOK
It was all about money.
You didn't lose your spot.
You just never had one to begin with.
But…
Then why did they tell me
it was because I'm an ex-con?
Who said that?
Who told you such a lie and why?
[Dosik] The day Mr. Ha died,
you were in the same elevator.
Plus, your recent contact
with Kim Gyeongae…
Was this all a coincidence?
-[♪ tense music playing]
-[sighs]
Answer the question.
When Ms. Kim Gyeongae was in prison,
I handled her psychiatric treatment.
I did it as a volunteer
before joining this hospital.
I met her a few times after her release.
I had meals with her
and checked in on her.
She seemed like a decent person.
I had no idea she'd go
and do something like this.
That's all.
-And that's why you kept this from us?
-Yes.
I didn't want to get involved.
When so many coincidences line up,
it means someone is lying.
Then go find out who's lying.
And next time,
bring me evidence, not accusations.
[phone buzzing]
[sighs]
Yeah.
What?
Right now?
Got it.
-[call ends]
-Let's continue another time.
For now, get yourself to safety.
Noh Manhui is on the way to the hospital.
[♪ suspenseful music playing]
WOORI TOGETHER MEDICAL CENTER
[phone buzzes]
Yeah, Detective Jang.
What?
[chimes]
[phone buzzes]
INCOMING CALL
HUSBAND
-[tires screeching]
-[buzzing continues]
[♪ dramatic music playing]
[gasps]
Ms. Ko.
[buzzing continues]
It's been a while.
Where's Mr. Kang?
MISSED CALL
[♪ dramatic music continues]
[breathing heavily]
Don't move, okay?
[foot tapping]
[hyperventilating]
I said don't move!
[screams]
[panting]
[banging on door]
[panting continues]
[breathing heavily] I said don't move.
[screams]
Are you all right?
Honey?
[grunts]
-[siren wailing]
-[panting]
Stay right here.
No! Don't go out there, honey!
[siren continues]
[♪ thrilling music playing]
STYLE
::cue()
-[panting]
-[door unlocks]
[Dosik] Ms. Ko!
-Are you okay?
-Uh…
[stammers] He went that way.
-Go, get after him!
-On it.
[siren continues]
Send medical assistance
to the basement stairwell.
[♪ thrilling music continues]
[Gyeongae] Excuse me.
Excuse me!
Is something going on outside?
[chains rattle]
Excuse me!
I said, is something going on out there?
Ms. Ko, take deep breaths.
Hold on.
What happened to her?
We found her in the basement parking.
She's in severe hyperventilation.
-[hyperventilating]
-I'll go with you. You're fine, Seyun.
Just breathe. Slowly. Inhale…
[horn honking]
[♪ music intensifies]
-[Taeju groans]
-[Manhui grunts]
[grunts]
[murmurs]
Hey, boss. Guess what?
This is all your fault.
-If you…
-[groans]
…had just given me the money you promised,
none of this would be happening.
Who put you up to it?
[grunts]
Who…
Who ordered you to kidnap my wife?
[Manhui] Ah.
That's what you want to know.
That's too bad.
You got it all wrong. [sighs]
[grunts]
Look, you got it all wrong.
[panting]
What?
I wasn't after your wife.
Hey, it was you.
[♪ mysterious music playing]
You're the one I was going to kill.
What are you talking about?
Me…
On whose orders? And why?
Does it really matter?
You're going to die either way.
So will your wife.
What?
Your wife.
They're going to kill her. [panting]
They've already tried once.
Someone tried to kill her?
They ordered Dr. Ha Jeongsoo…
to kill your wife.
And how do you know that?
Because I saved her.
[panting continues]
[groans]
But they'll try to kill her again.
[siren wailing]
[pipe clatters]
[siren continues]
Thanks.
It's a sedative.
You should feel better soon.
[gasps]
[sighs]
STYLE
::cue()
[siren wailing]
LAW ENFORCEMENT
Mr. Kang, are you okay?
[Taeju] Yeah, I'm fine.
You can't just go after him
by yourself like that.
[sighs]
WOORI TOGETHER MEDICAL CENTER
Excuse me, nurse.
What's going on out there?
-I'm here to change your IV bag.
-Yeah, okay,
but is something going on outside?
I'm talking to you.
-Why won't you answer me?
-Please don't move.
Your husband was here earlier.
[♪ mysterious music playing]
-[Taeju] Chiung.
-Hey.
How's Seyun?
Sedated for now.
It's acute stress.
Her body reacted since it was
similar to the trauma she suffered before.
How are you holding up?
Yeah, I'm fine.
[inhales]
Director Ko's inside.
Oh, okay. Thanks a lot.
[door closes]
What did she do to deserve this?
What are those damn cops doing?
What?
You still suspect me?
You still think I tried to have
my own daughter kidnapped
and that woman killed?
I don't even want to imagine
that you'd do such a thing to Seyun.
So…
let's be honest with each other.
I can't just stand by
and watch Seyun face danger anymore.
Kim Gyeongae…
You knew about her, didn't you?
[sighs]
Yes, I've seen her before.
I met her when she came in to apply,
with that damn husband of hers.
Kim Gyeongae…
I heard she was screened out
because she's an ex-con.
Is that true?
Who on earth told you that?
Am I wrong?
How the hell would I know
if that woman's an ex-con?
That's not on her application.
So she dared to kidnap my daughter
because she wasn't selected
for my project?
I see.
But you know,
that might actually be where it all began.
What?
Because it wasn't fair.
You went on about hope and excitement.
And who gets to enjoy them
all came down to money, didn't it?
That's not how I see it.
Donations fund our research,
which saves future patients.
That woman was denied
the opportunity to save her own life.
We can't save every patient.
I opted for the best option…
for a better future.
And I know…
my decision was the right one.
It's that greed of yours
that dragged us into this mess.
I hope you know that.
Father.
Besides you, me, and Dr. Ha,
STYLE
::cue()
who else knows about the hospital
using fetal stem cell samples?
[beeps]
[luggage thudding]
[phone buzzing]
SEONGJIN POLICE
DETECTIVE JANG DOSIK
[♪ suspenseful music playing]
[car beeps]
Long time no see.
How have you been?
But where are you off to in such a hurry,
Dr. Cha Myeonghui?
WOORI TOGETHER MEDICAL CENTER
[sighs]
[knocks on door]
-Yes?
-[door opens]
Are you doing okay?
You need to take it easy.
[door closes]
You look worse than I do.
You shouldn't have gone
after him like that. He's dangerous.
Well, you're
not the type to listen, anyway.
Anything else you want to tell me?
Yeah, there is.
What is it?
I thought it was about time you knew.
About our spinal cord project.
It was problematic from the beginning.
What do you mean?
The selection for the clinical trial…
It wasn't made fairly.
The spots were reserved
for the top donors from the get-go.
What?
What are you talking about?
The stem cells we were using in
our procedures weren't the approved ones.
They were illegally sourced
fetal stem cells.
[exhales]
There's no way.
Who made those decisions?
You see, I thought your father
had something to do with this.
That's why I asked you
to look for those files.
Kim Gyeongae was one
of the applicants who didn't make the cut.
She never stood a chance to begin with.
So is that why all of this is happening?
Because of my dad?
It's true that your father
made his share of mistakes,
but he wasn't behind your kidnapping.
I've confirmed that myself.
[scoffs]
[♪ intriguing music playing]
[door opens, closes]
STYLE
::cue()
[sighs]
Did you get any sleep last night?
[scoffs]
What about you?
It looked like you didn't sleep a wink.
[sighing] Gosh.
Stop worrying so much.
I've been checking in on Seyun at work,
and Taeju is with her.
You're right.
You have to stay strong
at times like this. [chuckles]
HAIR COLLAGEN 3270
Gosh.
I've been so out of it
that I completely forgot to take this.
No patient wants a hospital director
who looks more washed out than they do.
Take one every day. Don't forget.
[chuckles]
You know, I've noticed
that taking this makes a big difference.
[both chuckle]
It's also supposed
to be good for your skin.
You should take one too.
-Shall I?
-Mmm.
[sighs]
It already feels good. [chuckles]
Things will get better in time.
I hope so.
[chattering]
Oh, Dr. Kang.
Are you hurt at all from yesterday?
-No, I'm fine. But what's going on?
-[Dosik sighs]
Ms. Cha Myeonghui has fled.
What do you mean, she's fled?
You see, she was the last person
Mr. Ha was with
on the day he died,
which makes her a prime suspect.
Myeonghui?
She's known Kim Gyeongae
since she was in prison.
It seems like they've been
in touch after her release too.
Myeonghui was acquainted
with Kim Gyeongae?
Yes, we went to her house
with an arrest warrant,
but she'd already packed up
and disappeared.
BEHAVIORAL HEALTH
CONSULTATION ROOM
[knocks on door]
Come on in, Taeju.
Are you okay?
No.
[sighs]
Sounds like the talk didn't go so well.
STYLE
::cue()
[sighs]
I thought we'd been using
adult stem cells.
But we weren't.
They were fetal stem cells.
Fetal stem cells?
Yes.
So that's what it was.
Have you
told anyone else about it?
No, not yet.
Sorry for showing up out of the blue.
I had nowhere else
to sort my thoughts out.
No, it's good.
I'm glad you came.
I should tell Seyun, shouldn't I?
Taeju.
Uh…
You're still processing this right now.
Do you think Seyun would be
able to handle this if you told her now?
It'll just cause misunderstandings.
You may not have known about it,
but you've been using
illegal material in your procedures.
That much is true.
[sighs]
It's okay. It happens.
It's okay, Taeju.
Don't you worry.
This isn't the end.
[inhales]
I should be going.
Thank you for hearing me out.
Taeju.
Now's not the time.
You must not tell her.
[♪ tense music playing]
Never.
[Taeju] She knew all about it,
even before I told her.
Honestly, every time I saw you people,
I kept thinking, "Why would they do this?"
"Just why?"
"Why did they do this to my wife?
Why did they kidnap her?"
But to find out
that you were after me, not my wife…
That was kind of a shock.
How do you know that? Who told you?
Noh Manhui.
Your husband, Noh Manhui.
You met my husband?
He seemed quite shocked
when I told him Dr. Ha tried to kill you.
He was very worried about you.
So now…
your husband should know as well.
STYLE
::cue()
That you were both used and tossed aside.
Right before he died,
Dr. Ha met Myeonghui in the elevator.
After they talked,
he changed his destination,
and died moments later.
Dr. Cha was there with him?
Why?
Why are you so surprised
that those two ran into each other?
I've been thinking about it.
Myeonghui was in the know as well.
About what?
The fetal stem cells.
Was it Dr. Cha?
The one who lied to you
that your prior got you rejected?
I mean, you two
have been in touch all along,
since back when you were in prison.
Yeah, so what?
I mean, what's so wrong about that?
Ah.
You must think
you're in a different league
than a criminal like me, don't you?
But guess what?
You're the one who exploited
those dead babies
for your benefit, not me.
All I wanted…
I…
I just wanted to live.
It can't be Dr. Cha.
She always told me to never give up.
She said in that clinical trial,
they could make brand-new nerves
and put them into me.
She said she'd help me.
She told you that
they'd give you new nerves?
Dr. Cha said that to you?
She's a psychiatrist.
I mean, how could she possibly
help you in that situation?
Myeonghui…
introduced you to someone, didn't she?
I don't even know
what you're talking about.
What are you even saying?
She's gone off the grid.
What was she so afraid of?
Your husband ran away, Dr. Ha is dead,
and Myeonghui's disappeared.
So now…
you're all by yourself.
-[door closes]
-They're all the same.
They all use me and just toss me aside.
WING 102 ROOM 07
KIM G.A
STYLE
::cue()
FUND DONATION AGREEMENT,
CLINICAL TRIAL APPLICATION
DONATION: 100 MILLION WON
APPLICANT NAME: OH MINSEOK
STATUS: ACCEPTED
DONATION: 550 MILLION WON
APPLICANT NAME: LEE SEONGUK
STATUS: ACCEPTED
[gasps]
DONATION: 270 MILLION WON
APPLICANT NAME: PARK DOHYEON
STATUS: ACCEPTED
KIM JEONGHUI
DONATION: 190 MILLION WON
APPLICANT NAME: KIM GYEONGAE
STATUS: SCREENED OUT
[Seyun's mother] What are you doing here?
Why are you in your father's study?
Mom, did you know about this?
About what, dear?
About what Dad did.
[chuckles] What are you talking about?
Never mind. It's nothing.
Don't worry about it.
Wait, Seyun?
Seyun.
WOORI TOGETHER MEDICAL CENTER
FUND DONATION AGREEMENT
It was just as you said.
Why didn't you tell me?
Do I not deserve to know?
I had no idea what my dad had done.
But you knew all along.
Why did you make me out to be a fool?
It's not like that, Seyun.
Then what is it?
I just felt like I shouldn't tell you.
Why not?
Why did you think you shouldn't tell me?
Why?
[gasps]
Hold on.
That day…
The day we lost Hayun.
Were you late because…
[♪ suspenseful music playing]
The patients consented to the procedure
thinking it was their own stem cells.
This is completely illegal, Father.
Those illegal procedures
helped people regain movement
and stand on their own two feet.
They're hopeful
and excited about the future.
That is not hope.
Any hope that's built on a lie
is bound to fall apart.
Please count me out of this project.
STYLE
::cue()
What about Seyun?
What will you do about her?
Whether you do the surgery or not,
that's your call.
But it won't be you
who pays the price.
It will be Seyun.
[sighs]
Dr. Kang.
I mean, Taeju.
Do you think I've never felt that way?
I've been there.
But I had a family to protect.
I just had to suck it up.
That's how I've kept myself going.
Your heart,
your values, your morals…
Just put them all aside.
Don't let Seyun catch on.
It'd only hurt her, all right?
If you
really love her, please.
You're home.
Where were you all night?
Why are you out here?
You should be in bed.
You've been acting weird lately.
You're always late,
and I can never reach you.
Something came up.
[sighs]
Honey.
Are you hiding something from me?
I'm not.
You sure there's nothing going on?
I'm sure.
Fine.
Listen.
I'm your wife.
You have to tell me
if there is something going on.
I can tell you're having a hard time,
but you won't say anything.
[sighs]
Where's your wedding ring?
I took it off before surgery.
I probably left it in the office.
-I'm going to turn in.
-All right.
[door opens, closes]
Daddy.
Oh, hey, Hayun.
My goodness.
What are you doing up so late?
Waiting for you, Daddy.
Goodness, did you?
My sweet little girl.
[♪ intriguing music playing]
STYLE
::cue()
HOSPITAL DIRECTOR'S OFFICE
[Dr. Ko] Your heart…
Just put them all aside.
If you really love her, please.
[knocks on door]
-[life support beeping]
-[heart monitor beeping]
[♪ music intensifies]
Dr. Ko, your granddaughter has
just been brought into the ER.
-What? Hayun is here?
-Yes.
How bad is it?
It looks like she has
a cervical spine injury.
She needs emergency surgery.
Ms. Ko is looking for Dr. Kang.
Should I give him a call?
[nurse] Dr. Ko?
He's connecting nerve ends right now.
If he stops now,
the patient will never stand again.
Tell Dr. Park to take over
the surgery for now.
I'll talk to Dr. Kang
when he's done with this.
Wait, Doctor.
Can you wait until Dr. Kang gets here?
We don't have time.
We'll try our best.
Ms. Ko. I have to ask you
to wait out here.
CALLING
HUSBAND
[line ringing]
Come on, honey, pick up.
Please. Hayun is…
-[line disconnected]
-Where is he? Why won't he pick up?
-[line ringing]
-[breathing heavily]
Where on earth is he?
Okay, can you wrap this up for me?
-Okay.
[beeping]
[doctor] She's flatlining!
[heart monitor flatlining]
[doctor] Dr. Kang.
[sobbing]
Where have you been?
[sobbing continues]
I said, where have you been?
[sniffles]
STYLE
::cue()
Where have you been?
[♪ emotional music playing]
[sobbing] Answer me!
Why?
Why have you carried
that burden all by yourself?
I had no idea,
so I just kept blaming you.
Asking where you were,
why you never came,
and saying it was all your fault.
[sighs]
It must've been just as hard on you
after we lost Hayun.
Why you had changed so much
and why you'd become so silent…
I didn't even try to understand.
I just kept pushing you
to answer my questions,
without ever trying to hear you out.
[gasps]
You should've told me.
Why couldn't you just tell me?
I had no idea,
so all I could do was resent you.
I was afraid…
that you'd break down.
What?
Hayun is already gone, and I thought
the truth would push you over the edge.
That's
what I was…
so scared of.
I'm okay with you resenting me.
Even if you resented me and blamed me,
I'd stay by your side.
But…
if you found out the truth
and broke down, I…
I thought if that happened, I…
I might lose you too.
I was so scared of that.
I'm sorry.
[sighs]
[sobs] I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry, honey.
It must have been so hard.
You must've been living in hell, honey.
No.
I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry.
I'm sorry, honey.
You can tell me anything now, okay?
Don't keep it all bottled up inside!
[sighs]
Seyun.
They were never after you.
What are you talking about?
They were after me.
I'm the one they wanted to kill.
STYLE
::cue()
[phone buzzing]
Yeah.
[♪ tense music playing]
[grunts, choking]
Who are you? [panting]
[straining] Wait, who the hell are you?
[straining]
Hold on.
You had me do all your dirty work,
and now you feign ignorance?
What the hell are you talking about?
I heard about it all.
You tried to kill my wife, didn't you?
[choking]
So what now?
Who will save your wife if I die?
Who else do you think
will save your wife? [grunts]
[straining continues]
THE HUSBAND
[♪ closing theme song playing]
[Taeju] They offered to operate on her
if you killed me.
I'll operate on her.
But I have one condition.
Could Myeonghui really pull this off
all on her own?
What I'll say then is up to you, isn't it?
[Dr. Choi] Kang Taeju.
You've been the problem all along.
There are too many things
that can't be undone.
But we have to make right what we can.
[Manhui] Where's my wife?
I know you took her.
My husband will not let you
get away with this.
[Manhui] Keep your word.
I'll do as you say.
Translated by Hyun Sik Yoon